researchers have found a new method that
could be used to grow and stimulate
brain function in people who are comos
and even heal damaged spinal cords and
people who are paralyzed this technology
has so many uses and of course it
involves the tiny human brains we can
literally grow in jars if we want to
this involves using biohybrid technology
that means while it has mechanical or
electrical components it also has biotic
components they take human stem cells
grow them into human neural tissue so
the tiny human brains but they guide
them using a chip of sorts so what
you're looking at is a brain chip
interface and each one of those little
Wells is going to have a tiny human
brain the neural organoids grow outward
making projections and they interface
with the neural tissue this is not dis
similar to earlier research where you
found out that you could grow a brain
organoid just near the decapitated spine
of a mouse and it would grow projections
and could even use that muscle the
difference here is that it is guided now
one of the limitations is that brain
organoids are essentially fetal they can
grow an awful lot getting that brain to
grow back to them is more difficult so
they tend to take over the job they'll
grow axial projections and have
hybridized connections but the adult
brain tissue isn't super willing to grow
back does that mean they'll take over
probably not it's just the Quirk of the
technology now these little guys can be
directed to do a job to turn into
certain cell types and can be forced to
make brain wave they can be
stimulated with the fact that they can
interface with human brains or any kind
of brains really that means that we now
have the capacity to deliver stimulation
to a brain that we've never had before
it could save a lot of lives and you
know maybe help my crushed L4 because
it's not not a fun time one of the
things you may ask is can these be
interfaced with non- living things or
other organoids made from other cell
types the answer is yes in fact you can
grow not just a decapitated Mouse into a
brain organoid you can grow muscle
tissues all on their own and attach them
and they can learn how to use them the
benefit of this kind of technology in
part is that you can test medications on
muscle tissue and brain tissue without a
living thing needing to be part of it
the creepier Parts is that these could
be used for biohybrid robots
robots that are not just operated with a
human brain and you can do that it's
been done several times and with rat
brains but it means you can make an
entirely biological robot out of human
peace meal and operate it with a brain
organoid which has been done granted
they are simple I dig through the
literature so you don't have to let me
know if you want to know about this
horrific flesh thing technically these
are virtual organoid and virtual muscle
tissue but I don't like it
at all I do love the existential dread
that comes with a lot of scientific
advancements but I also really
appreciate the things that could be done
that'll make people's lives a lot better
save lives unfortunately probably not
going to be available to us I am still
on a wait list for stem cell therapy for
my L4 meanwhile brain
organoids science is indeed held back by
funding and sometimes ethics but those
should be there for a reason and other
times it's held back because of our
government